<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Space-Complexity on TheSillyScribbles</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/space-complexity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Space-Complexity on TheSillyScribbles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.140.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 12:41:49 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/space-complexity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Time &amp; Space Complexity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/time-space-complexity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 12:41:49 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/time-space-complexity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recently decided to dive back into data structures and algorithms (DSA). These are fundamental skills for any developer, regardless of the field you&amp;rsquo;re in, and mastering them can significantly sharpen your problem-solving abilities. Beyond that, DSA is also intellectually stimulating and—dare I say—fun, especially when you’re tackling challenges with a friend. Now seems like the perfect time to revisit these essential topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;solving-problems&#34;&gt;Solving Problems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In computer science, just like in life, there are often multiple ways to solve a single problem. Each solution comes with its own trade-offs—just like how different recipes for making a cake can require varying amounts of time, effort, and ingredients. Similarly, algorithms have different &amp;ldquo;costs&amp;rdquo; in terms of resources.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="background">Background</h2>
<p>I&rsquo;ve recently decided to dive back into data structures and algorithms (DSA). These are fundamental skills for any developer, regardless of the field you&rsquo;re in, and mastering them can significantly sharpen your problem-solving abilities. Beyond that, DSA is also intellectually stimulating and—dare I say—fun, especially when you’re tackling challenges with a friend. Now seems like the perfect time to revisit these essential topics.</p>
<h2 id="solving-problems">Solving Problems</h2>
<p>In computer science, just like in life, there are often multiple ways to solve a single problem. Each solution comes with its own trade-offs—just like how different recipes for making a cake can require varying amounts of time, effort, and ingredients. Similarly, algorithms have different &ldquo;costs&rdquo; in terms of resources.</p>
<p>When discussing algorithms, we typically focus on two major abstract resources: time and space. While these terms might seem straightforward, their impact on how we evaluate solutions requires a closer look. Let’s break them down.</p>
<h2 id="time-complexity">Time Complexity</h2>
<p>Time complexity is a measure of how the runtime of an algorithm increases as the size of the input grows. It helps us understand how efficient an algorithm is, especially as we deal with larger data sets. Time complexity is usually expressed using Big O notation, which describes the worst-case scenario—how the algorithm performs when the input is as demanding as possible.</p>
<p>For example, if an algorithm has a time complexity of O(n), it means the execution time increases linearly with the input size n. So, if you double the input size, the runtime will also approximately double. Here’s a visual representation of different time complexities and how they compare:</p>
<p><img alt="diagram" loading="lazy" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/7/7e/Comparison_computational_complexity.svg"></p>
<p>In this diagram, you can see how different time complexities (e.g., O(1), O(n), O(n^2)) grow as the input size increases. The goal is to minimize the time complexity for more efficient algorithms.</p>
<h2 id="space-complexity">Space Complexity</h2>
<p>Space complexity, on the other hand, measures how much memory an algorithm uses to solve a problem. This includes both the memory used by the input itself and any additional memory (auxiliary space) the algorithm requires during its execution.</p>
<p>For instance, if you’re sorting an array in place, your space complexity could be O(1) because you aren’t using any extra memory outside of the input. However, if the algorithm needs additional storage, such as an extra array for temporary data, the space complexity might increase to O(n).</p>
<p>Understanding space complexity is just as important as time complexity because, in some cases, memory usage can be the limiting factor, especially when working with large datasets or resource-constrained environments.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>Mastering time and space complexity is crucial for writing efficient algorithms. By learning how to evaluate and optimize these factors, you can make better decisions when solving problems and choosing the right approach for the task at hand. In future posts, I’ll explore specific algorithms, their complexities, and how to apply these concepts in real-world scenarios.</p>
<h2 id="references">References</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/big-o-cheat-sheet-time-complexity-chart/">Big O Cheat Sheet – Time Complexity Chart - freecodecamp</a></li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_complexity">Time Complexity - Wikipedia</a></li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Space_complexity">Space Complexity - Wikipedia</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
