<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TheSillyScribbles</title>
    <link>https://blog.kushagraj.xyz/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TheSillyScribbles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.7</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 20:58:29 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.kushagraj.xyz/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kishy&#39;s Guide to Photo Archival</title>
      <link>https://blog.kushagraj.xyz/posts/photo-archival/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 20:58:29 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.kushagraj.xyz/posts/photo-archival/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all have memories—and memories we desperately want to protect. Yet keeping those moments safe seems to be a fading idea as everything becomes so digitally transient and hard to preserve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I’m taking you on a journey I’ve been on myself: safeguarding the moments that mean the most—the story of our lives, our loved ones, and our identities. Because, honestly, isn’t that what life’s all about? I just want you to be able to lie in your 80s, looking at these preserved, disconnected moments that you once dismissed as trivial, slowly coming together into a narrative that makes you smile and cry at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>We all have memories—and memories we desperately want to protect. Yet keeping those moments safe seems to be a fading idea as everything becomes so digitally transient and hard to preserve.</p>
<p>Today, I’m taking you on a journey I’ve been on myself: safeguarding the moments that mean the most—the story of our lives, our loved ones, and our identities. Because, honestly, isn’t that what life’s all about? I just want you to be able to lie in your 80s, looking at these preserved, disconnected moments that you once dismissed as trivial, slowly coming together into a narrative that makes you smile and cry at the same time.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/c/c5/Instant_film_photos.jpg/1281px-Instant_film_photos.jpG"></p>
<p>So, shall we start?</p>
<h2 id="get-it-physical">Get it Physical</h2>
<p>Digital may feel fleeting, but I believe that printing your memories is the only way they’ll truly last. In the coming weeks, I’m planning to pick and choose my best pictures and get them printed on acid-free paper. (I’m also linking to ente&rsquo;s blog on physical photo archival, which covers everything you need to know about preserving physical photos.)<br>
<a href="https://ente.io/blog/how-to-preserve-physical-photos/">Read ente&rsquo;s blog here</a></p>
<h2 id="digital-storage">Digital Storage</h2>
<p>Now comes the inevitable digital part. Sure, if you have all your photos printed, that’s awesome—but given how many pictures we click these days, the cost and convenience of digital backups are too good to ignore. It makes sense to have multiple backups, so here are your options:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>M-Disk</strong><br>
M-disks are these fancy disks made with non-organic matter that claim to last for centuries. We haven’t lived long enough to fully test that, but they’re considered the gold standard for professional archival. Just don’t rely on them as your only backup.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/1/17/M-disc-comparison-blank-vs-written.jpg/1920px-M-disc-comparison-blank-vs-written.jpg"></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Hard Drives</strong><br>
Traditional spinning hard drives can last up to 10 years. I’m currently using two LUKS-encrypted drives—each about 5 years old—to store all my photos. It’s not ideal, but it’s what I can afford right now. Just remember to read and write to your drives at least once a year to keep them happy.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Cloud</strong><br>
This one’s controversial. I’m personally not a fan of the cloud, but if you decide to use it, you can technically tar up your files (or use another compression method), encrypt them with GPG, and then upload to any cloud service. Just be sure to use a strong password. It might serve as a good backup in case all your other copies fail.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="final-thoughts">Final Thoughts</h2>
<p>Preserving your photos is more than just a technical task—it’s an act of love and rebellion against time. Whether you’re meticulously printing your favorite memories or setting up multiple digital backups, every step you take is a promise to your past and a gift to your future.</p>
<p>So, get out there and start your photo archival. Your memories deserve nothing less than a thoughtful home—both in print and in bits.</p>
<p>Keep clicking, keep preserving, and above all, keep cherishing the moments that make you, you!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Do I Contribute to OpenStreetMap?</title>
      <link>https://blog.kushagraj.xyz/posts/why-i-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 20:14:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.kushagraj.xyz/posts/why-i-map/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to share why I contribute to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.openstreetmap.org/&#34;&gt;OpenStreetMap (OSM)&lt;/a&gt; and why you should care—or even consider joining in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-openstreetmap&#34;&gt;What is OpenStreetMap?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.openstreetmap.org/&#34;&gt;OpenStreetMap&lt;/a&gt; is an open database of geographic data (geo-data) that anyone can contribute to. Unlike maps controlled by profit-driven corporations, OSM is a purely community-driven project. Its mission is to create a comprehensive and freely accessible log of all geographic data on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Central London Map&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/f/f7/Soho_-_map_1.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-should-you-care&#34;&gt;Why Should You Care?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community Driven&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today, I want to share why I contribute to <a href="https://www.openstreetmap.org/">OpenStreetMap (OSM)</a> and why you should care—or even consider joining in.</p>
<h2 id="what-is-openstreetmap">What is OpenStreetMap?</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.openstreetmap.org/">OpenStreetMap</a> is an open database of geographic data (geo-data) that anyone can contribute to. Unlike maps controlled by profit-driven corporations, OSM is a purely community-driven project. Its mission is to create a comprehensive and freely accessible log of all geographic data on Earth.</p>
<p><img alt="Central London Map" loading="lazy" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/f/f7/Soho_-_map_1.png"></p>
<h2 id="why-should-you-care">Why Should You Care?</h2>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Community Driven</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>OSM is built by volunteers from all over the world, making it a shared resource owned by no single entity. This open model prevents corporate control over what data is added, modified, or prioritized.</li>
<li>Maps controlled by private companies often introduce issues like biased data inclusion and reduced privacy. OSM stands as a fair and equitable alternative.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>It&rsquo;s a Database</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>At its core, OSM is a database. This enables users to perform incredibly detailed and specialized tasks beyond what traditional maps offer. Whether it’s building navigation systems, analyzing urban infrastructure, or creating highly customized maps, OSM’s database unlocks limitless possibilities.</li>
<li><a href="https://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Main_Page">Learn more about using OSM data</a>.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="why-i-contribute">Why I Contribute</h2>
<p>For me, OpenStreetMap feels like a miniature digital version of Earth. It’s a recreation of our world, and contributing to it excites me. I see it as a way to make this virtual Earth as complete and accurate as possible.</p>
<p>Here are more reasons why I love contributing:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Granularity</strong>: OSM allows contributors to add incredibly minute details—things you’d never find on a corporate map. For instance, I’ve added over 50 shelters in Delhi to the map, which brings me a sense of pride and fulfillment. Beyond shelters, you can map basketball courts, football fields, gates, trees, and even park benches. The smallest contributions collectively make OSM an unparalleled resource.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Equitable Access</strong>: Earth belongs to all of us. By contributing to OSM, I’m helping ensure that geographic data remains freely accessible to everyone, regardless of background or location. This open access empowers individuals and communities in ways commercial maps never could.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Exploring Local Regions</strong>: Contributing to OSM motivates me to explore local areas that are often overlooked or underrepresented. Mapping these regions not only helps the database but also gets me more involved in my locality.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="join-the-movement">Join the Movement</h2>
<p>If you’ve ever felt frustrated by the limitations of traditional maps or simply want to make a difference, OSM is an incredible platform to explore. It’s not just about mapping—it’s about contributing to a global, community-driven project that benefits everyone.</p>
<p>Start small. Add a detail in your neighborhood, like a park or a missing road. Or go big and help map entire regions. Every contribution counts.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Ready to get started?</strong> Visit the <a href="https://www.openstreetmap.org/edit">OSM Editing Page</a> and start mapping today.</li>
<li><strong>Plan your mapping adventures:</strong> Check out <a href="https://osmcal.org/">OSM Calendar (osmcal)</a> for upcoming events and activities.</li>
<li><strong>Connect with the community:</strong> Join the <a href="https://mastodon.osm.in/">OSM India Mastodon community</a> for local discussions, updates, and support.</li>
</ul>
<p>Together, we can build the most complete and accessible geographic database ever created. Every click, every mapped detail, every contribution helps shape a world where geographic data remains open and free for all.</p>
<p>Happy mapping!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Manage Development Containers?</title>
      <link>https://blog.kushagraj.xyz/posts/how-i-manage-dev-containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 18:44:03 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.kushagraj.xyz/posts/how-i-manage-dev-containers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, I’ll share how I manage my development containers, why they’re essential for my workflow, and how you can integrate them into yours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-development-containers&#34;&gt;What Are Development Containers?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Development containers are isolated environments that function like sandboxed operating systems. Essentially, they’re self-contained operating systems that can run independently or with limited interaction with your host operating system (e.g., Windows, Linux, or macOS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;ships&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/f/f6/LMS_freight_containers_on_lorry_and_rail_wagon_%28CJ_Allen%2C_Steel_Highway%2C_1928%29.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can think of them as neat little cargo boxes, not interfering with each other.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In this blog post, I’ll share how I manage my development containers, why they’re essential for my workflow, and how you can integrate them into yours.</p>
<h2 id="what-are-development-containers">What Are Development Containers?</h2>
<p>Development containers are isolated environments that function like sandboxed operating systems. Essentially, they’re self-contained operating systems that can run independently or with limited interaction with your host operating system (e.g., Windows, Linux, or macOS).</p>
<p><img alt="ships" loading="lazy" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/f/f6/LMS_freight_containers_on_lorry_and_rail_wagon_%28CJ_Allen%2C_Steel_Highway%2C_1928%29.jpg"></p>
<p>You can think of them as neat little cargo boxes, not interfering with each other.</p>
<h2 id="why-do-they-matter">Why Do They Matter?</h2>
<p>Using development containers opens up a range of possibilities that make development more streamlined, flexible, and efficient. Here are some key benefits:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Platform-Specific Development</strong>: I can run Flutter development in a Debian-based container (since it’s officially supported) while keeping my host environment as Arch Linux.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Version Control</strong>: Containers allow me to work with specific versions of dependencies for a project without affecting or being affected by the versions on my host system.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Environment Consistency</strong>: Sharing the exact development environment with friends or teammates ensures that everyone works with the same setup, reducing “it works on my machine” issues.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="tools-for-managing-development-containers">Tools for Managing Development Containers</h2>
<p>You have several options for managing development containers. Here are two popular ones:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Distrobox</strong> (based on Podman):</p>
<ul>
<li>Provides tight integration with the host system.</li>
<li>Ideal for creating lightweight, flexible environments.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Docker</strong>:</p>
<ul>
<li>A more widely known solution with extensive community support.</li>
<li>Excellent for creating highly isolated and reproducible environments.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<p>These tools are your gateways to managing containers effectively.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-create-a-debian-distrobox-container">How to Create a Debian Distrobox Container</h2>
<p>If you want to create a Debian-based Distrobox container for Flutter development, follow these steps:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span class="line"><span class="cl">distrobox create flutter --image debian
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>After running this command, the required images will be pulled, and necessary packages will be installed. Once complete, you’ll have your Distrobox container ready to use as a development environment. From here, you can export applications, install development tools, and much more.</p>
<p><img alt="neofetch" loading="lazy" src="/posts/how-i-manage-dev-containers/neofetch-flutter.webp"></p>
<h2 id="final-thoughts">Final Thoughts</h2>
<p>Development containers are a game-changer for maintaining a clean, flexible, and reproducible workflow. Whether you’re juggling multiple projects, collaborating with a team, or experimenting with new tools, containers help you stay organized and efficient.</p>
<h2 id="references">References</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/devcontainers">Dev Containers Tutorial - Visual Studio Code</a></li>
<li><a href="https://docs.docker.com/">Official Documentation - Docker</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/89luca89/distrobox">Distrobox - GitHub</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Are Hashmaps?</title>
      <link>https://blog.kushagraj.xyz/posts/what-are-hashmaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 15:24:03 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.kushagraj.xyz/posts/what-are-hashmaps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we’ll discuss hashmaps—a fundamental data structure in computer science. I chose this topic while solving the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kushagra-xo/leetcode/tree/master/1.twoSum&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Two Sum&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; problem, which required the use of hashmaps to efficiently find a solution. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover hash functions, linked lists, and how they come together to form hashmaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hashing&#34;&gt;Hashing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start by understanding hashing. Hashing is a process of mapping variable-sized input data (like strings or numbers) to a fixed-size output. This mapping is carried out by a hashing function.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="background">Background</h2>
<p>Today, we’ll discuss hashmaps—a fundamental data structure in computer science. I chose this topic while solving the <a href="https://github.com/kushagra-xo/leetcode/tree/master/1.twoSum">&ldquo;Two Sum&rdquo;</a> problem, which required the use of hashmaps to efficiently find a solution. In this post, we&rsquo;ll cover hash functions, linked lists, and how they come together to form hashmaps.</p>
<h2 id="hashing">Hashing</h2>
<p>Let’s start by understanding hashing. Hashing is a process of mapping variable-sized input data (like strings or numbers) to a fixed-size output. This mapping is carried out by a hashing function.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/posts/what-are-hashmaps/hash_func.webp"></p>
<p>Hashing functions can produce outputs of different lengths. For example, a hash function that outputs 6 characters will always generate a string of exactly 6 characters.</p>
<p>However, this process creates a challenge. Since there are infinitely many possible inputs but only a finite number of possible outputs, collisions can occur. A collision happens when two different inputs generate the same output. While collisions are inevitable in theory, modern hash functions like SHA256 are designed to minimize their occurrence, making them exceedingly rare in practice.</p>
<p>Hashing is widely used beyond hashmaps. Some common applications include digital signatures, public key cryptography, and more.</p>
<h2 id="linked-lists">Linked Lists</h2>
<p>Now that we understand how hashing works, let’s move on to linked lists, which are crucial in handling collisions in hashmaps.</p>
<p>A linked list is a dynamic data structure that doesn&rsquo;t store elements contiguously in memory. Instead, each element points to the next element, forming a chain-like structure.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/posts/what-are-hashmaps/linkedList.webp"></p>
<h2 id="hashmaps">Hashmaps</h2>
<p>Hashmaps combine hash functions and linked lists to create a data structure optimized for fast data retrieval. Here&rsquo;s how it works:</p>
<p>First, we use a hashing function to compute the hash of a given key (our input), and also store the value a associated with it.
This hash is then used to determine the index in an array where the data is stored. We refer to these indices as buckets.
If a collision occurs (i.e., two keys hash to the same bucket), the collided elements are stored as a linked list at that bucket.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/posts/what-are-hashmaps/hashmap.webp"></p>
<p>By combining the quick lookup capabilities of hash functions with the flexibility of linked lists, hashmaps allow us to efficiently store and retrieve data, even when collisions occur.</p>
<h1 id="related">Related</h1>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hash_function">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hash_function</a></li>
<li><a href="https://crypto.stackexchange.com/questions/47809/why-havent-any-sha-256-collisions-been-found-yet">https://crypto.stackexchange.com/questions/47809/why-havent-any-sha-256-collisions-been-found-yet</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-linked-lists-work/">https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-linked-lists-work/</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time &amp; Space Complexity</title>
      <link>https://blog.kushagraj.xyz/posts/time-space-complexity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 12:41:49 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.kushagraj.xyz/posts/time-space-complexity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recently decided to dive back into data structures and algorithms (DSA). These are fundamental skills for any developer, regardless of the field you&amp;rsquo;re in, and mastering them can significantly sharpen your problem-solving abilities. Beyond that, DSA is also intellectually stimulating and—dare I say—fun, especially when you’re tackling challenges with a friend. Now seems like the perfect time to revisit these essential topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;solving-problems&#34;&gt;Solving Problems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In computer science, just like in life, there are often multiple ways to solve a single problem. Each solution comes with its own trade-offs—just like how different recipes for making a cake can require varying amounts of time, effort, and ingredients. Similarly, algorithms have different &amp;ldquo;costs&amp;rdquo; in terms of resources.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="background">Background</h2>
<p>I&rsquo;ve recently decided to dive back into data structures and algorithms (DSA). These are fundamental skills for any developer, regardless of the field you&rsquo;re in, and mastering them can significantly sharpen your problem-solving abilities. Beyond that, DSA is also intellectually stimulating and—dare I say—fun, especially when you’re tackling challenges with a friend. Now seems like the perfect time to revisit these essential topics.</p>
<h2 id="solving-problems">Solving Problems</h2>
<p>In computer science, just like in life, there are often multiple ways to solve a single problem. Each solution comes with its own trade-offs—just like how different recipes for making a cake can require varying amounts of time, effort, and ingredients. Similarly, algorithms have different &ldquo;costs&rdquo; in terms of resources.</p>
<p>When discussing algorithms, we typically focus on two major abstract resources: time and space. While these terms might seem straightforward, their impact on how we evaluate solutions requires a closer look. Let’s break them down.</p>
<h2 id="time-complexity">Time Complexity</h2>
<p>Time complexity is a measure of how the runtime of an algorithm increases as the size of the input grows. It helps us understand how efficient an algorithm is, especially as we deal with larger data sets. Time complexity is usually expressed using Big O notation, which describes the worst-case scenario—how the algorithm performs when the input is as demanding as possible.</p>
<p>For example, if an algorithm has a time complexity of O(n), it means the execution time increases linearly with the input size n. So, if you double the input size, the runtime will also approximately double. Here’s a visual representation of different time complexities and how they compare:</p>
<p><img alt="diagram" loading="lazy" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/7/7e/Comparison_computational_complexity.svg"></p>
<p>In this diagram, you can see how different time complexities (e.g., O(1), O(n), O(n^2)) grow as the input size increases. The goal is to minimize the time complexity for more efficient algorithms.</p>
<h2 id="space-complexity">Space Complexity</h2>
<p>Space complexity, on the other hand, measures how much memory an algorithm uses to solve a problem. This includes both the memory used by the input itself and any additional memory (auxiliary space) the algorithm requires during its execution.</p>
<p>For instance, if you’re sorting an array in place, your space complexity could be O(1) because you aren’t using any extra memory outside of the input. However, if the algorithm needs additional storage, such as an extra array for temporary data, the space complexity might increase to O(n).</p>
<p>Understanding space complexity is just as important as time complexity because, in some cases, memory usage can be the limiting factor, especially when working with large datasets or resource-constrained environments.</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<p>Mastering time and space complexity is crucial for writing efficient algorithms. By learning how to evaluate and optimize these factors, you can make better decisions when solving problems and choosing the right approach for the task at hand. In future posts, I’ll explore specific algorithms, their complexities, and how to apply these concepts in real-world scenarios.</p>
<h2 id="references">References</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/big-o-cheat-sheet-time-complexity-chart/">Big O Cheat Sheet – Time Complexity Chart - freecodecamp</a></li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_complexity">Time Complexity - Wikipedia</a></li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Space_complexity">Space Complexity - Wikipedia</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redragon K630: A Budget Mechanical Keyboard</title>
      <link>https://blog.kushagraj.xyz/posts/k630-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 23:50:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.kushagraj.xyz/posts/k630-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I needed a keyboard to pair with my Xiaomi Pad 6. The official Xiaomi keyboard didn’t seem worth its price given its subpar quality and limited use with the tablet alone. That’s when I realized I’d been wanting a mechanical keyboard for a while. I mean, it’s aesthetic, the sound is satisfying, and let’s face it—using one kind of makes you &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; more like a programmer. So yeah, I got it for all the wrong reasons, but honestly, I don’t think it was a bad investment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="background">Background</h2>
<p>Recently, I needed a keyboard to pair with my Xiaomi Pad 6. The official Xiaomi keyboard didn’t seem worth its price given its subpar quality and limited use with the tablet alone. That’s when I realized I’d been wanting a mechanical keyboard for a while. I mean, it’s aesthetic, the sound is satisfying, and let’s face it—using one kind of makes you <em>feel</em> more like a programmer. So yeah, I got it for all the wrong reasons, but honestly, I don’t think it was a bad investment.</p>
<h2 id="first-impressions">First Impressions</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/posts/k630-keyboard/with_lap.webp"></p>
<p>The unboxing experience was pretty standard—nothing fancy, but that’s what I expected given the price. One thing that stood out was the weight of the keyboard. It felt heavy in my hands, though I’m sure that’s just because this is my first mechanical keyboard, so I don’t have anything to compare it to.</p>
<p>Typing on it felt completely different from my laptop keyboard. Now, whenever I switch back to my laptop, its keyboard feels flat and lifeless in comparison. As for the sound—it’s not overwhelming, but it’s just enough to give that satisfying mechanical <em>click</em>. Anything louder might get annoying after a while, so this feels like the perfect balance. Oh, and the backlighting? It’s a nice touch, especially at night.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/posts/k630-keyboard/top.webp"></p>
<h2 id="issues">Issues</h2>
<p>One weird issue I’ve encountered—and this only happens when I use the keyboard with my tablet—is that the ESC key registers as the &lsquo;`&rsquo; character. I’m still figuring out why this happens, but it’s an odd quirk that I hope to resolve soon.</p>
<h2 id="final-thoughts">Final Thoughts</h2>
<p>All in all, I think this keyboard is a great addition to my setup, and I’m pretty happy with the purchase. It’s functional, aesthetically pleasing, and makes typing a more enjoyable experience. Plus, who doesn’t love a good mechanical keyboard, right?</p>
<h2 id="related">Related</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.redragonzone.com/products/redragon-k630-gaming-mechanical-keyboard">Redragon K630 - Official Website</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.mi.com/in/product/xiaomi-pad-6/">Xiaomi Pad 6 - Official Website</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Broadcasting Services Bill</title>
      <link>https://blog.kushagraj.xyz/posts/broadcast-bill/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 09:32:34 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.kushagraj.xyz/posts/broadcast-bill/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;India is on the verge of introducing a change in its media architecture with the proposed &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Broadcasting_Services_(Regulation)_Bill,_2023&#34;&gt;Broadcasting Services (Regulation) Bill, 2023&lt;/a&gt;. While the intention behind this bill seems noble—establishing control over a wider range of broadcasting services and implementing censorship—the implications are far-reaching and concerning for press freedom, privacy, and creative expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-consolidated-regulatory-framework&#34;&gt;A Consolidated Regulatory Framework&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proposed bill seeks to consolidate all broadcasting services, including digital platforms like social media, under a single regulatory framework. This move raises questions about the government&amp;rsquo;s intentions and potential control over what content is permitted in public discourse as we are well aware of the control established by the majority government in the past decade over journalistic independence and freedom. By expanding its reach to cover both traditional and digital mediums, the bill poses a significant threat to India&amp;rsquo;s digital journalism, which has played a crucial role in shaping public opinion and intellectual in the recent years, when the traditional forms of media were completely biased.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>India is on the verge of introducing a change in its media architecture with the proposed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Broadcasting_Services_(Regulation)_Bill,_2023">Broadcasting Services (Regulation) Bill, 2023</a>. While the intention behind this bill seems noble—establishing control over a wider range of broadcasting services and implementing censorship—the implications are far-reaching and concerning for press freedom, privacy, and creative expression.</p>
<h2 id="a-consolidated-regulatory-framework">A Consolidated Regulatory Framework</h2>
<p>The proposed bill seeks to consolidate all broadcasting services, including digital platforms like social media, under a single regulatory framework. This move raises questions about the government&rsquo;s intentions and potential control over what content is permitted in public discourse as we are well aware of the control established by the majority government in the past decade over journalistic independence and freedom. By expanding its reach to cover both traditional and digital mediums, the bill poses a significant threat to India&rsquo;s digital journalism, which has played a crucial role in shaping public opinion and intellectual in the recent years, when the traditional forms of media were completely biased.</p>
<h2 id="threats-to-press-freedom">Threats to Press Freedom</h2>
<p>The bill proposes strong content regulation through a separate committee responsible for regulating and censoring content on every service. This move raises concerns about the government&rsquo;s control over what can be reported and how journalists are expected to conduct themselves when sharing news or opinions. Additionally, the requirement for individual journalists and creators to register and follow broadcasting rules when commenting on news is troubling, as it could lead to self-censorship and stifle independent voices.</p>
<h2 id="the-dominance-of-government">The Dominance of Government</h2>
<p>The broadcasting advisory council in the proposed bill is dominated by government bureaucrats rather than independent voices. This move raises concerns about the potential for political influence over media content and the erosion of journalistic integrity. It also implies that the government will have a substantial role in shaping public discourse, which could lead to a suppression of dissenting views, highlights of which have very well been seen.</p>
<h2 id="privacy-concerns">Privacy Concerns</h2>
<p>The requirement for broadcasting network operators to maintain detailed subscriber data, including personal information, raises privacy concerns. This move can potentially expose individuals&rsquo; private information to unauthorized parties and create vulnerabilities for identity theft or surveillance. Furthermore, the collection and storage of such sensitive data could infringe upon citizens&rsquo; rights to privacy.</p>
<h2 id="call-to-action">Call to action</h2>
<p>As this proposed bill gains momentum in India&rsquo;s legislative process, it is essential that citizens, journalists, and media professionals take a stand against its potential dangers. Here are some steps you can take:</p>
<ul>
<li>Contact your local representatives and express your concerns about the bill.</li>
<li>Share your thoughts on social media using relevant hashtags such as #KillTheBill to raise awareness.</li>
<li>Support organizations and individuals who are fighting against the bill such as IFF (Indian Freedom Foundation).</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="resources">Resources</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://prsindia.org/files/parliamentry-announcement/2023-12-09/Draft_Broadcasting_Services_(Regulation)_Bill,_2023.pdf">Broadcasting Services (Regulation) Bill, 2023</a></li>
<li><a href="https://sansad.in/ls/members">Members of Parliament</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The PITX file format</title>
      <link>https://blog.kushagraj.xyz/posts/pitx-file-format/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 10:40:06 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.kushagraj.xyz/posts/pitx-file-format/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PITX is a file format that I have envisioned to create in the coming months as a new way to store digital media, a way where images are stored with their context, with their story, i.e. text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;inspiration&#34;&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every image tells a story, yet so many of these stories are lost due to the lack of appropriate textual context. This gap inspired me to create PITX, a new file format designed to store images along with their stories, bringing us back to the exact moments we cherish.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>PITX is a file format that I have envisioned to create in the coming months as a new way to store digital media, a way where images are stored with their context, with their story, i.e. text.</p>
<h2 id="inspiration">Inspiration</h2>
<p>Every image tells a story, yet so many of these stories are lost due to the lack of appropriate textual context. This gap inspired me to create PITX, a new file format designed to store images along with their stories, bringing us back to the exact moments we cherish.</p>
<h2 id="the-way-forward">The Way Forward</h2>
<p>I envision a future where galleries seamlessly integrate textual context with visual data, improving our interation. Adding and reading these stories should be as effortless as capturing the images themselves.</p>
<h2 id="current-progress">Current Progress</h2>
<p>I&rsquo;ve already begun developing the basic structure and functionality of the PITX file type. You can follow the progress and contribute at <a href="https://github.com/kushagra-xo/pitx">kushagra-xo/pitx</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Private Networks (VPNs)</title>
      <link>https://blog.kushagraj.xyz/posts/virtual-private-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 17:12:44 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.kushagraj.xyz/posts/virtual-private-networks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Virtual Private Networks act as an important tool in the modern digital landscape empowering many to protect their privacy, and circumvent government imposed censorship. What the people need is &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;choice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. The ability to choose what we wish to share and what we wish to access, and a VPN puts that power in your hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s talk some tech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-vpn&#34;&gt;What is a VPN?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A virtual private network (VPN) is a mechanism for creating a secure
connection between a computing device and a computer network, or
between two networks, using an insecure communication medium such as the
public Internet
&amp;ndash; &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_private_network&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Virtual Private Networks act as an important tool in the modern digital landscape empowering many to protect their privacy, and circumvent government imposed censorship. What the people need is <em><strong>choice</strong></em>. The ability to choose what we wish to share and what we wish to access, and a VPN puts that power in your hands.</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s talk some tech.</p>
<h2 id="what-is-a-vpn">What is a VPN?</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>A virtual private network (VPN) is a mechanism for creating a secure
connection between a computing device and a computer network, or
between two networks, using an insecure communication medium such as the
public Internet
&ndash; <cite><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_private_network">Wikipedia</a></cite></p></blockquote>
<p>They provide the ability to <em><strong>connect to remote computers, securely</strong></em>.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Security and privacy are two distinct concepts.
<cite> Read more here: <a href="https://www.privacyguides.org/en/basics/common-threats/#security-and-privacy">PrivacyGuides</a></cite></p></blockquote>
<p>But why do you care? By connecting to remote computers, you could
<em><strong>mask and tunnel</strong></em> all of your traffic through it. (VPNs are used differently in enterprise)</p>
<p>What do I mean by mask and tunnel?</p>
<ul>
<li>Mask
<ul>
<li>The source of all of your traffic now seems to be the VPN server. You forward all the relevant information to the server to make the connections for you. In more simple terms, now you start to pretend to be someone else over the internet, i.e. you start wearing a mask.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Tunnel
<ul>
<li>A secure tunnel is established between you and the VPN server, via encryption, such that the ISP cannot know what you&rsquo;re trying to access.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="basic-vpn-usage">Basic VPN usage:</h3>
<p><img alt="Normal VPN query" loading="lazy" src="/posts/virtual-private-networks/normal-vpn-query.webp"></p>
<p>A VPN shifts your trust from your ISP to a VPN server. Therefore choosing a VPN service is extremely crucial in determing privacy returns. A bad service will just be worse for your privacy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KDE Bluetooth Disabled on Login</title>
      <link>https://blog.kushagraj.xyz/posts/kde-bluetooth-on-login/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 13:03:03 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.kushagraj.xyz/posts/kde-bluetooth-on-login/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately i had been dealing with an issue where my bluetooth would disable automatically upon login. I had done a lot of troubleshooting to realize that the issue was with me &lt;em&gt;abruptly rebooting&lt;/em&gt; instead of rebooting via the gui.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which would cause &lt;code&gt;~/.config/bluedevilglobalrc&lt;/code&gt; to look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;[Adapters]
44:85:00:80:3C:BA_powered=false
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;solution&#34;&gt;Solution:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-comment-out-the-line-to-look-something-like-this&#34;&gt;1. Comment out the line to look something like this:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;[Adapters]
#44:85:00:80:3C:BA_powered=false
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have tested this and there does not seem to be any functionality issue whatsoever&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lately i had been dealing with an issue where my bluetooth would disable automatically upon login. I had done a lot of troubleshooting to realize that the issue was with me <em>abruptly rebooting</em> instead of rebooting via the gui.</p>
<p>Which would cause <code>~/.config/bluedevilglobalrc</code> to look something like this:</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>[Adapters]
44:85:00:80:3C:BA_powered=false
</code></pre><h2 id="solution">Solution:</h2>
<h3 id="1-comment-out-the-line-to-look-something-like-this">1. Comment out the line to look something like this:</h3>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>[Adapters]
#44:85:00:80:3C:BA_powered=false
</code></pre><p>I have tested this and there does not seem to be any functionality issue whatsoever</p>
<h3 id="2-make-the-file-read-only-or-immutable">2. Make the file read-only or immutable</h3>
<ul>
<li>Change the file to look like this:</li>
</ul>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>[Adapters]
44:85:00:80:3C:BA_powered=true
</code></pre><div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span class="line"><span class="cl">$ chattr +i ~/.config/bluedevilglobalrc
</span></span></code></pre></div><hr>
<h3 id="update-sun-nov-12-111746-am-ist-2023">Update: (Sun Nov 12 11:17:46 AM IST 2023)</h3>
<p>The issue does not seem to persist anymore, atleast for me, it&rsquo;s been a while since anything weird happened with my bluetooth. If you are still facing issues maybe you can try the above, or report relevant bugs at bugs.kde.org for better support.</p>
<h2 id="references">References:</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ManjaroLinux/comments/12fgj3o/kde_plasma_bluetooth_not_automatically_powered_on/">https://www.reddit.com/r/ManjaroLinux/comments/12fgj3o/kde_plasma_bluetooth_not_automatically_powered_on/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://bugs.kde.org/show_bug.cgi?id=469119">https://bugs.kde.org/show_bug.cgi?id=469119</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
