<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dsa on TheSillyScibbles</title>
    <link>https://blog.kushagraj.xyz/tags/dsa/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dsa on TheSillyScibbles</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 15:24:03 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.kushagraj.xyz/tags/dsa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What Are Hashmaps?</title>
      <link>https://blog.kushagraj.xyz/posts/what-are-hashmaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 15:24:03 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.kushagraj.xyz/posts/what-are-hashmaps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today, we’ll discuss hashmaps—a fundamental data structure in computer science. I chose this topic while solving the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kushagra-xo/leetcode/tree/master/1.twoSum&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Two Sum&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; problem, which required the use of hashmaps to efficiently find a solution. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover hash functions, linked lists, and how they come together to form hashmaps.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;hashing&#34;&gt;Hashing&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let’s start by understanding hashing. Hashing is a process of mapping variable-sized input data (like strings or numbers) to a fixed-size output. This mapping is carried out by a hashing function.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time &amp; Space Complexity</title>
      <link>https://blog.kushagraj.xyz/posts/time-space-complexity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 12:41:49 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.kushagraj.xyz/posts/time-space-complexity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recently decided to dive back into data structures and algorithms (DSA). These are fundamental skills for any developer, regardless of the field you&amp;rsquo;re in, and mastering them can significantly sharpen your problem-solving abilities. Beyond that, DSA is also intellectually stimulating and—dare I say—fun, especially when you’re tackling challenges with a friend. Now seems like the perfect time to revisit these essential topics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;solving-problems&#34;&gt;Solving Problems&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In computer science, just like in life, there are often multiple ways to solve a single problem. Each solution comes with its own trade-offs—just like how different recipes for making a cake can require varying amounts of time, effort, and ingredients. Similarly, algorithms have different &amp;ldquo;costs&amp;rdquo; in terms of resources.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
